Inventory of the Far Eastern Commission records
Hoover Institution Archives
Far Eastern Commission records
1945-1952
80198
Far Eastern Commission.
30 manuscript boxes (12 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives
Mimeographed minutes, memoranda, reports, laws, and proclamations, relating to Allied administration of occupied Japan after World War II.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1980.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
Allied commission for the supervision of the occupation of Japan.
Scope and Content of Collection
The documents of the Far East Commission, spanning a period between November of 1945 and March of 1952, represent the broad agenda of the eleven-nation commission tasked with planning the operations and policies of post World War II Japan. Meeting minutes, commission documents, and memoranda have been arranged by month. Documents from the seven major committees identified in the container list, include meeting minutes, notes from the secretary general, agendas, and issuances. Correspondence and reports are also included, often prefaced by secretary general Nelson T. Johnson.
Japan--History--Allied occupation, 1945-1952.
- Calendar of Papers, August 1946- January 1947 (Box-folder 1: 1-2)
- Schedule of Far Eastern Commission Meetings by Week, May 1946- May1948 (Box-folder 1: 3-4)
- Report by Secretary General of the F.E.C., February 1946- June 1950 (Box-folder 1: 5)
- Status of Papers, Far Eastern Commission, June 1946- June 1947 (Box-folder 1: 6)
- Annual Reports, February 1947- October 1948 (Box-folder 1: 7)
- Press Releases and Public Records, April 1947- June 1950 (Box-folder 1: 8)
- Meeting Minutes, February 1946- December 1947 (Box-folder 2: 1-4)
- Meeting Minutes, January 1948- September 1948 (Box-folder 3: 1-5)
- Meeting Minutes, October 1948- June 1949 (Box-folder 4: 1-4)
- Meeting Minutes, July 1949- July 1951 (Box-folder 5: 1-4)
- Summary of Commission Business, June 1946- April 1949 (Box-folder 5: 5)
- History of F.E.C. documents, May 1947- December 1948 (Box-folder 6: 1-5)
- History of F.E.C. documents, July 1949- December 1951 (Box-folder 7: 1-2)
- Committee No.1: Reparations, March 1946- October 1946 (Box-folder 7: 3-4)
- Committee No.1: Reparations, November 1946- July 1947 (Box-folder 8: 1-4)
- Committee No.1: Reparations, August 1947- September 1948 (Box-folder 9: 1-4)
- Committee No.1: Reparations, October 1948- March 1952 (Box-folder 10: 1-2)
- Committee No.2: Economic and Financial Affairs, March 1946- July 1946 (Box-folder 10: 3)
- Committee No.2: Economic and Financial Affairs, August 1946- May 1947 (Box-folder 11: 1-4)
- Committee No.2: Economic and Financial Affairs, June 1947- February 1948 (Box-folder 12: 1-4)
- Committee No.2: Economic and Financial Affairs, March 1948- April 1949 (Box-folder 13: 1-4)
- Committee No.2: Economic and Financial Affairs, May 1949- April 1951 (Box-folder 14: 1-2)
- Committee No.3: Constitution and Legal Reform, March 1946- December 1946 (Box-folder 14: 3-5)
- Committee No.3: Constitution and Legal Reform, January 1947- December 1948 (Box-folder 15: 1-4)
- Committee No.3: Constitution and Legal Reform, January 1949- April 1951 (Box-folder 16: 1)
- Committee No.4: Strengthening of Democratic Tendencies, March 1946- December 1947 (Box-folder 16: 2-5)
- Committee No.4: Strengthening of Democratic Tendencies, January 1949- April 1951 (Box-folder 17: 1)
- Committee No.5: War Criminals, November 1945- December 1951 (Box-folder 17: 2-3)
- Committee No.6: Aliens in Japan, March 1946- December 1946 (Box-folder 17: 4)
- Committee No.6: Aliens in Japan, January 1947- December 1951 (Box-folder 18: 1-2)
- Committee No.7: Disarmament of Japan, April 1946- April 1951 (Box-folder 18: 3-4)
- F.E.C. General and Correspondence, May 1946- December 1951 (Box-folder 19: 1-2)
- F.E.C. Economic General, Technology, and Economic Stabalization, May 1946- December 1951 (Box-folder 19: 3-5)
- Memorandum for Information General, March 1946- April 1947 (Box-folder 20: 1-4)
- Memorandum for Information General, June 1947- June 1948 (Box-folder 21: 1-5)
- Memorandum for Information General, July 1948- January 1949 (Box-folder 22: 1-4)
- Memorandum for Information General, February 1949- May 1949 (Box-folder 23: 1-4)
- Memorandum for Information General, June 1949- October 1949 (Box-folder 24: 1-4)
- Memorandum for Information General, November 1949- April 1950 (Box-folder 25: 1-5)
- Memorandum for Information General, May 1950- November 1951 (Box-folder 26: 1-4)
- Memorandum for Information Committee No.1, August 1946- August 1947 (Box-folder 26: 5)
- Memorandum for Information Committee No.1, September 1947- January 1950 (Box-folder 27: 1-3)
- Memorandum for Information Committee No.1, March- June 1950 (Box-folder 28: 1)
- Memorandum for Information Committee No.2, March 1946- September 1948 (Box-folder 28: 2-4)
- Memorandum for Information Committee No.2, October 1948- November 1950 (Box-folder 29: 1)
- Memorandum for Information Committee No.3, October 1946- June 1949 (Box-folder 29: 2)
- Memorandum for Information Committee No.4,5,6,7, October 1946- February 1950 (Box-folder 29: 3)
- Steering Committee Materials, February 1946- June 1946 (Box-folder 29: 4)
- Steering Committee Materials, July 1946- May 1948 (Box-folder 30: 1-4)